>>Our next question is from Student Kirk Charles,
我们的下一个问题来自学生 Kirk Charles
and he has quite a story here.
他在这儿有一个相当不错的叙述
Okay, "So we know Peter is very excited about launching his
好 “我们知道彼得对发布他的新的搜索引擎业务
new search engine business." This is true.
感到非常兴奋” 这是真的
SearchWithPeter.info is actually launched.
SearchWithPeter.info 确实上线了
>>It's a really cool site >>Yeah I put a lot of work into it
- 它确实是一个非常棒的网站 - 对 我为它做很多工作
Web 2.0 and all that.
Web 2.0 还有其他一切
"Let us suppose he is targeting the underserved
“我们假设他正在把目标放在政府扶持力度不大的
market of Klingon language web searches.
克林贡语言(《星际迷航》中克林贡人使用的语言)网络搜索市场
Let us suppose also that he is writing some
我们还假设他正在写一些
custom hashing procedure. After 8 months of
专门的哈希函数 8个月后
explosive growth in business," I hope so, "Peter finds that
业务量有爆炸性增长” 我希望如此 “彼得发现
he needs to double the number of buckets in his hash table.
他需要将哈希表中的桶的数量翻一番
He also finds that the hash buckets are not utilized evenly,
他还发现由于没透彻地理解克林贡语的哈希搜索方法
since he did not understand the hashing of Klingon
哈希桶的使用并不均匀”
very well." Sounds like a hard problem.
听起来是个挺难的问题
So, his question is "How can we re-hash the index
所以 他的问题是 “我们怎样才能在服务不中断的情况下
without service interruptions? This is made more difficult
重新计算索引? 这样一个事实让问题变得更困难
by the fact that his user base may get violent,
如果他推迟给出搜索结果
if he delays search results. Additionally the long latency
他的基础用户会变得具有攻击性  此外 大的星际网络时延
of intergalactic networks means he also needs to carefully
意味着他需要谨慎地
roll out a new hash."
推出新的哈希表”
Which strategy should he, I guess I, take?
他 我想是我 应该采取哪个策略?
>>Wow, well this is quite a question from Captain Kirk.
哇 Kirk 舰长的问题确实很不错
I'm glad he is hoping for the success of SearchWithPeter.info.
我真高兴他正在期待 SearchWithPeter.info 的成功
And thinking about the future is an important thing to do
并且 思考未来是一件非常重要的事
I think one thing I understand is Klingon name servers don't
我觉得我了解的一件事情是克林贡域名服务器
support the ".info" domain. So I think you're probably
不支持域名 .info 所以我觉得你现在大概
safe from the Klingon attack for now, but it's a good
安全地避开了克林贡人的攻击 但是当你重新构建哈希表时
question to think about when you have to re-hash a table.
它是一个好的思考题
So we've been talking about
我们已经讨论了
the standard way a hash table works. Once the
一个哈希表正常的工作方式
buckets get too full, or the load factor is too high,
一旦桶太满 或者负载量过高
you want to create a new table with more buckets,
你想创建一个新的有更多桶的哈希表
and you've got to copy all your entries to it.
并且你得将所有的元素拷贝到新的哈希表
If you're running a big service like SearchWithPeter.info,
如果你正在维护一个大的类似 SearchWithPeter.info 的服务
you don't want to shut down your service while you do that.
当重建哈希表时你不想关闭你的服务
That would get people pretty annoyed.
那样会让人相当恼火
If they're Klingons, you don't want to get them annoyed.
如果他们是克林贡人 你不会想让他们生气的
So what you could do instead and there are lots of
那么 你会怎么做来替代老的哈希表呢 可以做很多
different things, and I don't know what Google does,
不同的事情 虽然我不知道谷歌是怎么做的
I'm sure there are lots of solutions that are possible,
我确信有很多可能的解决方法
and they've figured out something that works well.
他们已经搞清楚某些有效可行的东西
One thing to do would be start a new copy,
一个事情是开始一个新的拷贝
so you keep the search engine going, still responding
这样 你让搜索引擎持续运行
to queries using the old hash table
仍然使用老的哈希表回应搜索请求
but you start a separate process of running on
但是你在不同的电脑上开始一个独立的运行进程
a separate computer, something that's making a new
做的事情是生成一个新的
copy of the hash table with a larger number of buckets.
包含大量桶的哈希表的拷贝
Then when you're done with that, you switch them over and
接着 当你把这些做完 你把它们切换过来
you have the larger table with new buckets going.
你以后就一直让那个更大的包含新桶的哈希表工作
Other than the switch over, there's no interruption
当你这样做 除了切换的时候
in service when you do that. There's some things
服务都没有中断 有些东西
that make this hard. You've gotta worry about
使得这种方法很难实现 你不得不担心
"Well what if a new entry is added to the hash
“嗯 当你在拷贝哈希表的过程中
table while you're in the middle of copying it."
如果有一个新的录入要添加到哈希表中怎么办”
You could lock it, make it so you can't add add any new
你可以锁死它 使它在那个时段
entries during that time. That might be a bad thing
不能再添加任何新的录入 如果拷贝的时间过长
if it takes a long time to copy. You could
那将是件糟糕的事情
maybe add the entry to both hash tables.
你或许可以把这个录入添加到这两个哈希表中
Every time a new entry is added, you add it to
每一次添加一个新的录入
both the original one and the copy as you're developing it.
你把它加入到原始的和你正在开发的这两个哈希表里
You could save the updates and apply them all later
你可以将更新存起来 然后在你完成拷贝之后
after you finish the copy.
再把它们全部应用起来
So there are lots of tough problems to solve
为了使搜索引擎持续工作
to make this work without interruptions,
还有很多困难的问题需要解决
but it's definitely an important question to think about
但是 这绝对是一个重要的需要考虑的问题
if you're building SearchWithPeter.info,
如果你正在构建 SearchWithPeter.info
and you have a lot of angry Klingons.
那么你会有很多怒气冲冲的克林贡用户
>>I probably should have been taking notes. >>Depending on the service.
- 大概我应该正在做笔记 - 取决于服务的好坏
Well, we'll see. Hopefully the Klingons
嗯 是这样的 希望克林贡人
don't know where you live.
不知道你住在哪
>>We've recently reached 50 users
我们最近已经有了50个用户
on SearchWithPeter.info.
使用 SearchWithPeter.info 了
We had a cake, and threw a party, it was pretty cool.
我们吃了一个蛋糕 举行了一场聚会 聚会是相当酷的
>>Cool, congratulations >>Thank you.
- 那太棒了 恭喜你 - 谢了